SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Professional Summary

Motivated Senior Software Engineer highly effective at developing new programs and fixing problems with existing systems in robust code for high-volume businesses. Strong decision-maker with 6 years of experience in software engineering and application development. Effective coach and mentor and committed to leading exceptionally gifted teams. Proven history of developing useful, efficient and cost-effective projects.

Skills

- Ruby 2.x.x, SQL
- Rails 4.x. 5.x
- Html, Css, JavaScript, Ajax, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, React 16.8
- Rspec, Capybara

- Docker, Azure DevOps, Bamboo, Git, Bitbucket
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server,
- Apache 2.0, Nginx
- Unix shell script, Linux

Work History

01/2021 to Current

Software Engineer Mastech Digital, Inc. â€" Columbia, SC

- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- Apply advanced troubleshooting techniques to provide unique solutions to our customer's individual needs
- Installed and configured software applications and tested solutions for functionality.
- Learn and use groundbreaking technologies such as MySql / ElasticSearch / Redis / Cassandra / MongoDB / Kafka / Spark / Databricks / Fivetran, etc.
- Leverage your extensive customer support experience to provide feedback to internal Punchh teams on how to improve our platform
- Work on critical, highly complex problems that may span across multiple programming languages and databases technologies
- Improve system performance, scalability and high availability
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for data extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Interfaced with cross-functional team of business analysts, developers and technical support professionals to determine comprehensive list of requirement specifications for new applications.

02/2017 to 12/2020

Software Engineer Mastech Digital, Inc. â€" Columbus, OH

- Delivered and maintained scalable system to support high-availability Bond management Application with various SPA applications.
- Having experience in writing clean code by implementing clean architecture an architectural pattern that can alleviate most of the pain, and a
 few design patterns that can take care of rest. The basic premise is to separate the Web layer from any business logic and separate business
 logic from database and remote access.
- Developed and tested many features in an AGILE environment using Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap.
- Configured routes between React JS and Rails to render the templates from the server-side. Used React JS with Redux to separate data and presentation layer. Utilized Redux stores to handle the states.
- Used JavaScript, jQuery for user interactions in pages. Creating a responsive web application integrating Twitter Bootstrap and React
 and media queries. Involved in design with database developers and business and created various Database objects such as tables,
 functions, stored procedures, database triggers and Indices as per business requirements.
- Implemented design and development of schedule jobs for auto-renewing bonds and processing payment information to Lawson using delayed Job active record and delayed job recurring gems.
- Created **Restful http services** to interact with UI and Handled caching for API's.
- Had build automated deployment process using Azure DevOps.
- Automated and implemented backup and recovery procedures for Azure build pipelines system that resulted in Deployment process.
- Monitored automated build and continuous software integration process to drive build/release failure resolution.
- Pinpoint and solve Ruby application performance issues down to the line of code using New Relic APM.
- Assist in developing test plans, conducting system tests, documenting and analyzing performance data.
- Development is managed using agile Kanban development methodology delivering releases to UAT and staging each four-week period.
- Interactive in providing change requests, trouble reports and requirements collection with the client.
- Manage, collaborate, and coordinate the work of an off-shore development team. Planned and carried out daily scrums, weekly estimations
 and retrospectives and pair programming.

09/2015 to 02/2017

Software Engineer Mastech Digital, Inc. â€" Des Plaines , IL

- Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving client requirements.
- Responsible for writing code in TDD and Object Oriented Programming supported by Ruby on rails in Agile SCRUM environment.
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Created controllers, helpers, models, views, and partials in the application with HTML5, CSS3 standards and also implemented services, domains and storage layers using Ruby, Rails.
- Implemented the searching of restaurant using the Google Places API and Google analytics to keep track of website traffic.
- Implemented facebook login using Oauth, and also added facebook tab page to access application in end user own facebook page.

- Involved in **Database Migration** using Active Records Action Controller, Active Resources, Fixtures and Action View in Rails.
- Implemented the Text message ordering, in order to process previous order from mobile text, using Twillio Api service.
- Integrated payment gateway (Payeezy) to Clovermenu application to process transactions.
- Implemented application dashbaord to keep track of monthly data using Highcharts Plugin.
- Implemented sorting, auto completer (typo ahead) and paginations functionality for entire application.
- Collaborated with Product Management and User Experience experts regarding product definition, schedule, scope and project-related decisions.
- Used Rails finder methods, filters, implemented soft deletes and model scopes in the application.
- Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the website using the HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Ajax and Jquery.

05/2013 to 05/2014

Systems Engineer Adobe Systems Incorporated â€" Hillsboro, OR

- Worked closely with customers, internal staff and other stakeholders to determine planning, implementation and integration of systemoriented projects.
- Monitored and tested application performance to identify potential bottlenecks, develop solutions, and collaborate with developers on solution implementation.
- Escalated project-related issues quickly to team lead and supported solutions. Provided 2nd and 3rd level technical support and troubleshooting to internal and external clients.
- Managed use of various types of databases and configured, installed and upgraded new ones.

Education 12/2015

Master of Science : Computer Science University Of Central Missouri - City

04/2013

Bachelor of Science: Electrical, Electronics And Communications Engineering

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University - City